Okay, so let's look at the solution.
では この答えを見てみましょう
If you said either layout_width or layout_height,
Layout widthもしくはLayout height という予想でしたら
those wouldn't be bad guesses.
間違っていないです
It's really important to choose these values carefully as as they
これらのvalueは 今後 スペースなどに影響を与えるので
affect the space that your element takes up.
注意して選ばないといけません
For example let's talk about layout_width.
例えば Layout widthを 取り上げてみましょう
Suppose that I have a text box that says, hi.
テキストボックスに hiと書くとします
And I set the layout_width to be wrap content.
そして layout widthを wrap contentとする
By default,
初期化の状態なので
this will just stick that text box into the upper left-hand corner.
テキストボックスは左上の端に 表示されます
Then, if I use another attribute to push it over to the right,
別のアトリビュートを使うと テキストボックスをもう少し右側に
the text box will be here.
移せます
If instead,
もしも
I use match parent, by default, hi will still be in the upper left-hand corner.
match parentを使うと 「こんにちは」は 再び左上の端に表示されます
But if I then try to set an attribute to push it to the right,
もしアトリビュートを使って 右側に動かそうとすると
it'll try to push this text box to the right.
また右側に移すことが できます
But it already is as far right as it could be because it's expanding
しかし match parentと全体像に 充分なくらい大きくなるので
to match the parent and fill the whole view group.
これはすでに充分右側にあります
In the case of using match parent,
match parentを使う場合
we can see that the hi text hasn't actually moved.
こんにちはは 実際 動いていないことが 分かります
So one thing that's hopefully clear for this example is that we're going to
この例でひとつ明快になっていることは
want to set both layout_width and layout_height to wrap content.
wrap contentでは layout widthと layout heightの両方を使うことです
So it wraps exactly around the content and
つまり コンテントを確実に ラップしているので
then when you tell the TextView to be either to the right, left, above,
TextViewに左右上下の指令を出すと
below, it'll actually move that text to that location.
そこの場所に移すことができます
Okay, so both layout width and layout height are important.
だから layout widthとlayout heightは 両方大事です
TextStyle is an attribute for bolding or italicizing text, and
TextStyleは太字やイタリックの アトリビュートなので
it really doesn't involve positioning or spacing.
テキストの位置やスペースには 関係ありません
Orientation is an attribute used specifically with linear layouts,
Orientationはlinear layoutの 時のみ使うアトリビュートで
to determine whether they are going to be vertical or horizontal.
テキストが縦になるか横になるか 決定します
Because we're using a relative layout this also doesn't make any sense.
私たちはrelative layoutを使って いるので これは関係ないですね
Layout_weight is really useful for spacing out elements evenly but again,
Layout weightは要素を均一に並べる ことができ便利ですが
this is a linear layout attribute.
これもlinear layoutの アトリビュートです
Which leaves us with these attributes.
だから 残りのアトリビュートを 使います
All of these attributes have to do with relative layouts.
このアトリビュートは全て relative layoutと関係あります
Now these attributes layout_to Right Of and layout_below are categorically
この Layout_to Right OfとLayout_belowは layout_alignParentのBottom leftやrightとは
different than the layout_alignParent either Bottom left or right.
全く違うものです
These attributes take two child views and
これらのアトリビュートで 2つのchild viewを
position them relative to one another.
相互関係の位置に置くことができます
For example, we could say position from Lyla to the right of and
例えば Lylaよりを 誕生日おめでとう Ben TextViewの
below the happy birthday Ben TextView.
右下とします
Let's see what that would like like.
どうなるか見てみましょう
Okay, so if we did that and
もしこれをした場合
we just looked at the two TextViews, this is the code that we would use.
2つのTextViewを見ていることになります これがコードです
With the happy birthday Ben TextView, I've created an ID here.
誕生日おめでとう BenのTextViewの IDはここです
And then I refer to that ID from the from Lyla TextView with the layout below
そして そのIDを参照し LylaよりのTextViewを アトリビュートの
and layout right of attributes.
layout 下 layout右とします
Here's a picture of what that actually looks like in the app and unfortunately,
これがその写真です 不運なことに
that didn't really do what we wanted.
私たちの想定しているものと異なります
The From Lyla view is in fact to the right of
Lylaよりのviewは 誕生日おめでとうBen TextViewの
the Happy Birthday Ben TextView.
右側にあります
And it is also below, but it's not in the lower right-hand corner.
下にありますが 右側の下の方ではありません
So these two aren't correct.
よって この2つは正しくないです
Okay, so that leaves us with these three attributes,
つまり私たちに残されているのは この3つのアトリビュートで
which will take my TextView and
これらは私のTextViewを考慮し
align them in relation to the Parent, which happens to be the whole screen.
Parentにたいして一列に並べます これがスクリーン全部に表示されているもの
Now I want From Lyla to be down here.
Lylaよりがこの下の
Which is in the lower right-hand corner of the parent.
parentの右側の角に来るようにしたいのです
So I'm not going to be using layout_alignParentLeft, so in fact I
layout_alignParentLeftは使わないです
will be using layout_alignParentRight and layout_alignParentBottom.
そのかわり layout_alignParentRightと layout_alignParentBottomを使います
Let's see how this all comes together in the code.
コードだとどのようになるか 見て行きましょう
Okay, so first things first.
まずは
I'm going to find the From Lyla TextView and iIm going to make sure that
Lyla よりTextViewを見つけ layout widthとlayout heightが
the layout width and the layout height are both set to wrap_content otherwise,
両方ともwrap_contentにセットされている ことを確認します そうしないと
even if we position our textview correctly it might not actually move.
TextViewが合っていても 予想通りの動きを見せない時があります
Next I'm going to add the additional attributes.
次に 追加のアトリビュートを 付け加えます
For the value, I go ahead and put true.
valueはtrueとします
This is affirming that I want this TextView to be aligned
これで このTextViewが Parentの右に一列に並べられることを
to the Parent's Right.
認めたことになります
The other value I could put here is false, but that would mean
もう一つの可能性である Falseとした場合
that it is false that it aligns to the Parent Right, which is not what I want.
Parentの右に一列に並べられることを 不可としており これは違いますね
So now I'm going to type the other attribute to put at the bottom.
では もう一つのアトリビュートを 書き
And I will also set this to true.
これもtrueとセットします
All right, so for those of you at home this might be a little bit hard to see
はい自宅生には 少し分かり難いかもしれないですが
but it seems like we've positioned our view down here correctly.
これで正しくviewを セットできました
That said, let's see if it actually shows up correctly on the phone
では 実際にきちんと表示されるのか
by pressing the green Run button.
緑のRunボタンを押して 確認してみましょう
Okay, I select my phone and I click OK.
では 自分の携帯を選び OKをクリックしました
Okay, awesome.
完璧
So up here I have my Happy Birthday, Ben, and down here, I have From Lyla.
ここに誕生日おめでとうBenがきて 下にLylaよりがきています
And with that,
これで
everything looks like it's pretty much in the correct position.
全て正しいポジションに 位置づけできました